“尼比鲁 - M级行星”
哇靠！那是我们的交通工具耶！
Damn it, man! That was our ride! You just stunned our ride!
你竟然把牠电晕！
怎么不早说
Oh, great.
快跑！
Run!
你到底拿了什么？
What the hell did you take?
不知道，但他们在对着它拜
I have no idea, but they were bowing to it.
寇克呼叫航天飞机一号
Kirk to Shuttle One.
原住民已离开危险区域，地方清空了！
Locals are out of the kill zone.
史巴克，阻止火山活动然后离开这里！
You are clear. Repeat.
Spock, get in there, neutralize the volcano and let's get out of here.
我们得马上行动！
We have to do this now! I told the Captain
我跟舰长说过航天飞机承受不了这种温度
the shuttle wasn't built for this kind of heat.
舰长，原生物种有看到你吗？
Captain, did the indigenous life forms see you?
没有，史巴克，没看到
No, Mr. Spock, they did not.
最高指导原则明定
The Prime Directive clearly states
不可干涉外星物种的发展
there can be no interference
我知道啊！所以我才变装在丛林奔跑！
with the internal development of alien civilizations.
I know what it says! Which is why I'm running
through the jungle wearing a disguise!
快把超级冰块丢下去，我们才能离开！
Now drop off your super ice cube and let's go! Kirk out!
你准备好了
You're good.
如果真的要做，就得马上行动！
If we're gonna do this, we've got to do it now!
推进器的线圈快被火山灰毁了
This ash is killing our coils.
你确定不要我代替你去吗？
You sure you don't want me to go instead?
这样不合逻辑，我已经穿戴…
That would be highly illogical as I am already outfitted...
开玩笑的
Spock, I was kidding.
交给你了    - 不出发就来不及了！
- You got this. - Guys! We have to go! Now!
他们是真的想杀了我们！
They're trying to kill us!
吉姆，他们是真的想杀了我们！
They're trying to kill us, Jim!
90秒后见
I'll see you in 90 seconds.
就是现在！
Do it, do it!
Prerequisite change, 2-7-3...
“引擎过热”
I can't hold this position.
我无法维持位置
Spock, I've got to pull you back up.
史巴克，我得把你拉回来
Negative. This is our only chance to save this species.
不行，这是拯救此物种的唯一机会
如果火山爆发，这个星球就会毁灭
If this volcano erupts, the planet dies.
把他拉回来，马上！
Pull him back up. Now!
史巴克，你还好吗？
Spock, are you okay?
我居然…
I am,
…还活着，请稍候
surprisingly, alive. Stand by.
我们必须去救他，我要换装下去
We have to get him back. I'll suit up. I'm gonna go down.
我们得弃船
We have to abandon the shuttle.
我们不能抛下他！
- We can't just leave him, Sulu! - We don't have a choice!
我们别无选择！
Uhura, I'm sorry.
乌胡拉，对不起
史巴克，我们要先回企业号
Spock, we're going back to the Enterprise.
我们会回来救你的
We'll get you out of there.
舰长，我必须放弃航天飞机
Captain, I'm ditching the shuttle.
你们得想办法回企业号
You've got to make it to the Enterprise on your own.
太好了
Wonderful!
准备好要游泳了吗？    - 准备好了
- Uhura! You ready to swim? - I'm ready.
Jim!
吉姆！海滩在那边！
Jim! The beach is that way!
我们没有要去海滩！
I know! We're not going to the beach!
不…不会吧！
Oh, no, no, no!
我讨厌这样！
I hate this!
我知道！
I know you do!
把星舰藏在海底实在是太荒谬了！
Do you have any idea how ridiculous it is
to hide a starship on the bottom of the ocean?
还停了一整晚！海水…
We've been down here since last night!
史考特！史巴克呢？
The salt water's gonna ruin the...
Scotty! Where's Spock?
还在火山里
Still in the volcano, sir.
舰长抵达舰桥！
Captain on the bridge!
联络得到史巴克先生吗？
Lieutenant, do we have an open channel to Mr. Spock?
热度影响了通讯，但联络上了
The heat's frying his comms, but we still have contact.
史巴克？
Spock?
我已经启动装置了，倒数结束之后
I have activated the device, Captain.
产生的反应会让火山回归到休眠状态
When the countdown is complete,
the reaction should render the volcano inert.
到时他也会一睡不起
Yeah, and that's gonna render him inert!
可以使用传送器吗？
Do we have use of the transporters?
在这种磁场中不可能
- Negative, sir. - Not with these magnetic fields.
想办法把史巴克传送回来
I need to beam Spock back to the ship.
Give me one way to do it.
除非我们飞到火山口的正上方
Maybe if we had a direct line of sight.
这可是活火山耶！如果它爆发…
- If we got closer... - Hold on, wee man!
You're talking about an active volcano!
我不保证我们能承受得起那种高温！
Sir, if that thing erupts,
I cannae guarantee we can withstand the heat!
我不觉得能维持那种高度
I don't know that we can maintain that kind of altitude.
航天飞机还能隐藏在灰烬云里
Our shuttle was concealed by the ash cloud,
但企业号太大了
but the Enterprise is too large.
如果你们尝试救援…
If utilized in a rescue effort,
就会让原生物种发现我们的存在
it would be revealed to the indigenous species.
史巴克，没有人比你更了解规则…
Spock, nobody knows the rules better than you,
但凡事必有例外
but there has got to be an exception.
没有，这会违背最高指导原则
None. Such action violates the Prime Directive.
闭嘴，史巴克，我们是想救你！
Shut up, Spock! We're trying to save you, damn it!
多数人的利益胜过少数人的利益
Doctor, the needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few.
史巴克，我们在说的是你的命！
Spock, we're talking about your life!
无论如何都不能打破规定
The rule cannot be broken...
史巴克！
Spock!
快修复通讯
Try to get him back online.
离引爆时间还有90秒
Ninety seconds to detonations.
如果史巴克跟我易地而处
If Spock were here and I were there, what would he do?
他会怎么做？
他会让你死
He'd let you die.
史巴克！
Spock!
你没事吧？
You all right?
你让他们看见我们的星舰了
Captain, you let them see our ship.
他好得很
He's fine.
舰桥呼叫寇克舰长    - 什么事？
- Bridge to Captain Kirk. - Yes, Lieutenant.
史巴克中校上船了吗？
Is Commander Spock on board, sir?
他没事
- Safely and soundly.
请通知他，装置成功启动了
Please notify him that his device
has successfully detonated.
听到没？恭喜你，史巴克
You hear that? Congratulations, Spock.
你刚救了他们的世界
You just saved the world.
舰长，你违反了最高指导原则
You violated the Prime Directive.
被他们看见又有什么了不起
Oh, come on, Spock. They saw us. Big deal.
星际迷航  暗黑无界 （三区台版官方字幕）
“伦敦 - 星历2259.55”
“皇家儿童病理医院”
我能救她
I can save her.
你说什么？
What did you say?
你女儿
Your daughter.
我能救她
I can save her.
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
吉姆，不要理它
Oh, Jim. Come on, let it go.
你不会真的要去接吧？
Jim!
You're not actually gonna answer that, are you?
“星舰总部 - 旧金山”
Spock, I'm telling you, this is why he called. I can feel it.
我们被选上了，我感觉得到
不管你怎么感觉
Your feeling aside, I consider it highly unlikely
我不认为会选我们出这次任务
that we will be selected for the new program.
不然帕克为什么要找我们？
Why else would Pike want to see us?
他们给了我们最新的船
Forget about seniority.
不派我们还能派谁出去？
They gave us the newest ship in the fleet.
我想得到很多人选
I mean, who else are they gonna send out?
史巴克，这是个五年的任务耶！
I can think of numerous possibilities.
A five-year mission, Spock!
在太空深处探险！
That's deep space! That's uncharted territory!
未探索过的地区！那该有多棒
Think how incredible that's gonna be.
妳们好，我是吉姆寇克
Hey, ladies. Jim Kirk.
“平淡无奇”    - 什么？
- "Uneventful." Admiral?
你舰长日志上形容尼比鲁星的探勘任务
It's the way you described the survey of Nibiru in your captain's log.
我不想写太多以免浪费你时间
Yes, sir, I didn't want to waste your time going over the details.
谈谈那座火山吧，资料说它很活跃
Tell me more about this volcano.
如果它爆发，会摧毁整个星球
Data says it was highly volatile.
If it were to erupt, it would wipe out the planet.
那希望它不会爆发啰
Let's hope it doesn't, sir.
我有种预感它不会爆发了
Something tells me it won't.
这个嘛…大家对“活跃”的定义不一样
Well, sir, volatile is all relative.
也许资料出了问题
Maybe our data was off.
或是史巴克在火山里引爆冷聚变装置
Or maybe it didn't erupt
because Mr. Spock detonated a cold fusion device
然后一个还没发明轮子的文明…
inside it right after a civilization
that's barely invented the wheel
看见星舰从海里飞出来
happened to see a starship rising out of their ocean!
你是这样写的没错吧？
That is pretty much how you describe it, is it not?
你写了报告？怎么不告诉我？
- Admiral... - You filed a report?
我以为你舰长日志里会写事实
Why didn't you tell me?
I incorrectly assumed that you would be truthful in your captain's log.
我会啊，如果我不用救你一命的话
Yeah, I would have been if I didn't have to save your life.
我很感激你，所以我要把我的行为…
A fact for which I am immeasurably grateful
and the very reason I felt it necessary
责任还真重大啊，小尖
to take responsibility for the actions...
你的行动高尚，只会害我背黑锅
Take responsibility, yeah.
That'd be so noble, pointy,
if you weren't also throwing me under the bus.
小尖？你是在嘲笑我的…
"Pointy"? Is that a derogatory reference to...
够了
Gentlemen.
星际舰队的任务是探索观察，不是干涉
Starfleet's mandate is to explore and observe, not to interfere.
如果顺利，原生物种不会发现我们介入
Had the mission gone according to plan, Admiral,
the indigenous species would never
不要狡辩
have been aware of our interference.
我是瓦肯人，喜欢讨论
That's a technicality.
I am Vulcan, sir. We embrace technicality.
你在耍嘴皮子吗？
Are you giving me attitude, Spock?
我讲了很多话，你指的是哪句？
I'm expressing multiple attitudes simultaneously, sir.
出去
To which are you referring?
Out.
中校，你可以走了
You're dismissed, Commander.
你知道你这个人有多麻烦吗？
You have any idea what a pain in the ass you are?
我大概知道，长官
I think so, sir.
那你到底哪里错了？学到什么教训？
So tell me what you did wrong.
What's the lesson to be learned here?
永远不要相信瓦肯人
Never trust a Vulcan.
你连这都答不出来，你在报告里说谎
Now, see, you can't even answer the question. You lied.
你认为你不需要遵守这些规则…
On an official report, you lied.
因为你不认同它们
You think the rules don't apply to you
这是你找我入伍的原因
'cause you disagree with them.
这是你给我星舰的原因
That's why you talked me into signing up in the first place.
我把星舰给你，是因为看到你的潜力
It's why you gave me your ship.
I gave you my ship because I saw a greatness in you.
但现在的你是如此的傲慢
And now, I see you haven't got an ounce of humility.
那我该让史巴克去死？    - 你搞错重点
What was I supposed to do, let Spock die?
换成是你会怎么样？
You're missing the point.
I don't think I am, sir. What would you have done?
我根本不会让我的大副去冒险！
I wouldn't have risked my First Officer's life
你是去观察这个星球不是改变它的命运
in the first place!
You were supposed to survey a planet,
not alter it's destiny!
你违反了一堆规定，差点害死全船的人
You violated a dozen Starfleet regulations
and almost got everyone under your command killed.
可是我没有！我没有损失任何船员…
Except I didn't!
这就是你的问题，你以为你永远是对的
You know how many crew members I've lost? Not one!
That's your problem, you think you're infallible!
以为规则是给别人用的
You think you can't make a mistake.
It's a pattern with you!
有些规则是这样
- The rules are for other people! - Some should be.
你还用好运去合理化自己的上帝情结
And what's worse is you using blind luck
to justify your playing God!
这件事已经引起马可士上将的注意
Given the circumstances,
this has been brought to Admiral Marcus's attention.
他召开了一个我不能参加的裁决会议
He convened a special tribunal, to which I was not invited.
你也知道星际舰队会怎么做
You understand what Starfleet regulations mandate
be done at this point.
他们解除了你对企业号的指挥权
They've taken the Enterprise away from you.
要把你送回星舰学院
They're sending you back to the Academy.
上将，听我说…
Admiral, listen...
为什么要我听？除了自己，你谁也不听
- No, I'm not going to listen. - I can justify...
Why should I listen? I'm not going to listen.
You don't listen to anybody but yourself!
我的每个决定…
I understand regulation, but every decision I've made...
不！我不要听！
No! I can't listen!
你不遵守规定，你也不负责任
You don't comply with the rules,
you don't take responsibility for anything,
你根本不尊敬舰长这个职位
and you don't respect the chair.
你知道为什么吗？
You know why?
因为你还没准备好
Because you're not ready for it.
“伦敦”
“凯文号纪念数据库”
Attention, personnel.
Blue security clearance now permitted for airlock access.
I'm going to need three titanium...
Radiation protection is required in this area.
“讯息送出  接收者马可士上将”
你怎么找到我的？
How did you find me?
我比你想象中更了解你
I know you better than you think I do.
最开始我就是在这种地方找到你
The first time I found you was in a dive like this.
还记得吗？你被痛殴的那次
Remember that? You got your ass handed to you.
没有吧
No, I didn't.
没有？    - 事情不是你说的那样
- You don't? - No, that's not what happened.
你被打得超惨的    - 才没有
- That was an epic beating. - No, it wasn't.
你鼻孔里还塞着卫生纸
You had napkins hanging out of your nose.
有没有？
Did you not?
那次真的打得很爽
Yeah, that was a good fight.
还爽咧
"A good fight."
这就是你的问题
I think that's your problem right there.
他们把船还给我了
They gave her back to me.
企业号
The Enterprise.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
你要小心你的大副
Watch your back with that First Officer, though.
史巴克不会跟着我，他被调职了
Spock's not going to be working with me.
He's been transferred.
星舰布莱伯利号
U.S.S. Bradbury.
你是我的新大副
You're going to be my First Officer.
花了点时间才说服马可士
Yeah, Marcus took some convincing.
但我有时也能想到好论点
But every now and then I can make a good case.
你怎么说的？
What did you tell him?
说实话
The truth.
我说我相信你
That I believe in you.
应该给吉姆寇克第二次机会
That if anybody deserves a second chance, it's Jim Kirk.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
这倒挺新鲜的
That is a first.
不会有事的
It's going to be okay, son.
“紧急会议，德斯仲会议室”
"Emergency session, Daystrom."
我们得走了
That's us.
Yeah.
快着装
Suit up.
"Woman". All Starfleet personnel, please be advised,
舰长
- new security protocols are in effect. - Captain.
我不是舰长了，是大副
Not anymore, Spock. First Officer.
我被降级，你被调职了
I was demoted and you were reassigned.
情况没有更糟已经很幸运了
It is fortunate that the consequences
你开什么玩笑
were not more severe.
舰长，我也不希望…
You've gotto be kidding me.
我不是舰长
Captain, it was never my intention...
Not Captain.
我救了你一命
I saved your life, Spock.
你写一份报名，我的船就没了
You wrote a report, I lost my ship.
中校，我应该告诉你我写了报告
Commander, I see now I should have alerted you
to the fact that I submitted the report.
我知道你超爱遵守规定的，但我做不到
No, I'm familiar with your compulsion
to follow the rules. But you see, I can't do that.
如果有人救我一命，我绝不会背叛他
Where I come from, if someone saves your life,
瓦肯人没办法说谎
you don't stab him in the back.
Vulcans cannot lie.
我是在跟你人类的那一半血统说话
Then I'm talking to the half-human part of you.
你知道为什么我会回去救你吗？
All right?
Do you understand why I went back for you?
史巴克中校？
Commander Spock? Frank Abbot, U. S. S. Bradbury.
星舰布莱伯利号，艾伯特舰长
看来你要跟着我了
Guess you're with me.
是的，舰长
Yes, Captain.
老实说…
The truth is
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you.
马可士上将，请
Admiral Marcus, sir.
谢谢你们这么快就赶来
Thank you for convening on such short notice.
请坐
Be seated.
我想有些人已听说伦敦的攻击事件
By now, some of you have heard what happened in London.
攻击目标是舰队数据库
The target was a Starfleet data archive.
现在变成一个大洞，死了42个人
Now it's a damned hole in the ground,
42 men and women are dead.
一小时前，我收到一个讯息
One hour ago,
I received a message from a Starfleet officer,
有个舰队军官坦承犯案，说是被逼的
who confessed to carrying out this attack,
that he was being forced to do it by this man,
逼他的是约翰哈里森中校，自己人
Commander John Harrison. He's one of our own.
他要为这个恐怖行为负责
And he is the man responsible for this act of savagery.
不知为何，约翰哈里森对星际舰队宣战
For reasons unknown, John Harrison has just declared
a one-man war against Starfleet.
我们绝对不能让他逃出联邦领域
And under no circumstances are we to allow this man
to escape Federation space.
你们是本区域所有的星舰高阶将领
You here tonight represent the senior command
of all the vessels in the region.
为了给死者交代，你们要找出这个混蛋
And in the name of those we lost,
you will run this bastard down.
这是个搜捕行动，开始吧
This is a manhunt, pure and simple, so let's get to work.
没有离开地球的曲速讯号，他还在这
Earth's perimeter sensors have not detected
any warp signatures leaving the system,
so we know he can't be far.
你们的船要维持封锁队形
You will park your ships in a blockade formation
然后派出搜索船和登陆队去追查
then deploy search vehicles and landing parties
to run down every lead.
这个人残杀无辜百姓
This man has shown willingness to kill innocent people,
所以交战法则很简单
so the rules of engagement are simple.
遇到他时，如果怕自己或旁人受伤
If you come across this man and fear for your life
or the lives of those nearby,
可以选择使用致命武力
you are authorized to use deadly force on sight.
袋子装了什么东西？    - 先别吵
- What's in the bag? - James, not now.
攻击数据库很怪吧？就像去炸图书馆
It doesn't seem odd to you that he'd target an archive?
It's like bombing a library.
克里斯？你没事吧？
Chris? Everything okay there?
没事，寇克只是不适应自己的新职位
Yes, sir. Mr. Kirk is just acclimating
to his new position as First Officer.
寇克，你有什么想法就说吧，集思广益
You got something to say, Kirk, say it.
Tomorrow's too late.
我没有意见，对不起
I'm fine, sir. My apologies.
说吧，别害羞
Spit it out, son. Don't be shy.
为什么要攻击数据库？
Why the archive?
信息是公开的，如果他想伤害星际舰队
All that information is public record.
If he really wanted to damage Starfleet,
这恐怕只是个开始而已
this could just be the beginning.
什么的开始？
The beginning of what, Mr. Kirk?
受到攻击时，程序规定要求…
Sir, in the event of an attack, protocol mandates
舰长和大副必须到总部集合…
that senior command gather captains and first officers
at Starfleet H.Q., right here
…到这个房间
- in this room. - It is curious Harrison
哈里森抢没有曲速引擎的小艇也很怪
would commandeer a jumpship without warp capabilities...
快离开这里！
Clear the room!
Woman, No!
快派出空中防卫小组！德斯仲会议室！
We need an air defense team! Daystrom Conference Room!
- Let's go! - Cover me!
- Target acquired. - Take him out!
Watch my flank!
快走，快走！
- Go, go, go! - Cover me!
开火！
Guard 13 Fire!
中校，史考特在小艇的残骸有发现
Yeah?
Commander, Mr. Scott has found something
in the wreckage of Harrison's ship.
他要求我们立刻过去
He has asked to see us right away.
在坠毁的小艇找到的，他是用这逃走的
Captain! I found this in the crashed jumpship, sir.
什么玩意？
- This is how the bastard got away. - What do you mean?
携带式超曲速传送器
It's a portable transwarp beaming device.
你知道他到哪里去了吗？
Well, can you figure out where he went?
我查过了，但你不会想知道的
I already did, sir. And you're no gonna like it.
他跑到唯一一个…
He's gone to the one place we...
…我们不能去的地方
We just can't go.
上将，他不在地球上了
Admiral, sir, he's not on Earth.
他在克罗诺斯
He's on Kronos, sir.
我要求恢复指挥职权，并允许我去抓他
I request my command be reinstated
and your permission to go after him.
你们先走吧
Give us a minute.
- 克罗诺斯？    - 是的，长官
- Kronos. - Yes, sir.
哈里森跑去克林贡人母星，想要投诚？
So Harrison's gone to the Klingon homeworld.
我们不确定
- Is he defeating? - We're not sure, sir.
他躲在克莎省，那里没有人住
He has taken refuge in the Ketha Province,
他一定是想躲在那里
a region uninhabited for decades.
He's gotta be hiding there, sir!
他知道我们进入克林贡领空会引起战争
He knows if we even go near Klingon space,
星际舰队不能去追他，我可以单独去
it'd be all-out war.
Starfleet can't go after him, but I can.
拜托，长官
Please, sir.
已经无法避免和克林贡人开战
All-out war with the Klingons is inevitable, Mr. Kirk.
其实我觉得早就打起来了
If you ask me, it's already begun.
自从知道他们的存在，克林贡帝国…
Since we first learned of their existence,
the Klingon Empire has conquered and occupied
已经占领了两个星球，还常攻击我们
two planets that we know of
and fired on our ships half a dozen times.
他们一定会打来的
They are coming our way.
伦敦遇袭的不是数据库
London was not an archive.
是极机密的星舰分部，称为31区
It was a top-secret branch of Starfleet
designated Section 31.
他们在发展防卫科技，训练人员…
They were developing defense technology
and training our officers to gather intelligence
并搜集克林贡和其它潜在敌人的情报
on the Klingons and any other potential enemy
who means to do us harm.
哈里森本来是我们最优秀的探员
Harrison was one of our top agents.
他现在却是逃犯，我想解决他
Well, now he's a fugitive and I want to take him out.
帕克一直说你是最优秀的人才
Pike always said you were one of our best and brightest.
你真该听听他是怎么帮你辩护的
You should have heard him defend you.
是他召募你加入舰队，对吧？
He's the one who talked you into joining Starfleet, wasn't he?
是的
Yes, sir.
那他有没有说是谁召募他的？
Did he ever tell you who talked him into joining?
是我害死他的
His death is on me.
我不能再害你
And yours can't be.
史巴克，你说哈里森躲在荒芜地区？
Sir, please. All I...
Mr. Spock, you said the province
是的
where Harrison is hiding is uninhabited?
Affirmative, sir.
31区研发出了一种…
As part of our defensive strategy,
…新型防卫用光子鱼雷
31 developed a new photon torpedo.
射程远、无法追踪，克林贡人侦测不到
Long-range and untraceable,
it would be invisible to Klingon sensors.
你可以去解决他，但不能冒险
I don't want you hurt, but I want to take him out.
在中立区边缘锁定哈里森的位置
You park on the edge of the Neutral Zone,
you lock onto Harrison's position,
用鱼雷杀了他，然后马上离开
you fire, you kill him and you haul ass.
请让史巴克重新担任我的大副
Permission to reinstate Mr. Spock as my First Officer.
同意
Granted.
吉姆！
Jim!
你跑哪去了？    - 怎么了？
- Where were you? - For what?
你要做身体检查，你才刚经历枪战
Your medical exam.
Ten hours ago, you were in a damn firefight.
老骨头，我很好
- Now it's my duty as ship's... - I'm fine, Bones.
好个屁
The hell you are.
我真的没事
I'm fine.
史巴克，进度报告
Status report, Mr. Spock.
企业号等我们到就可以出发
The Enterprise should be ready for launch
by the time we arrive.
很好
- Good. Good. - Captain.
舰长
谢谢你提出我的复职请求
Thank you for requesting my reinstatement.
不客气
You're welcome.
身为大副，我必须反对这次任务的规范
As I am again your First Officer, it is now my duty
to strongly object to our mission parameters.
老样子，不意外
Of course it is.
按规定不能跳过审判直接处决嫌犯
There is no Starfleet regulation
that condemns a man to die without a trial,
你和马可士上将都忘了这点
something you and Admiral Marcus are forgetting.
而且无故对克林贡母星发射鱼雷违反…
Also, preemptively firing torpedoes
at the Klingon homeworld goes against...
那里什么都没有，只会死一个人
You yourself said the area's uninhabited.
There's only gonna be one casualty.
我们的命令也和舰队规定无关
And in case you weren't listening,
our orders have nothing to do with Starfleet regulation.
我们要用鱼雷射克林贡人？
Wait a minute. We're firing torpedoes at the Klingons?
先不管规定，我们做的事很不道德
Regulations aside, this action is morally wrong.
不管规定，把你从火山救出来才是对的
Regulations aside, pulling your ass out of a volcano was morally right.
但我做了你却没有称赞我
And I didn't win any points for that.
冷静点
Whoa, Jim, calm down.
我不必让机器人帮我上道德课
I'm not gonna take ethics lessons from a robot!
嘲笑我是防卫心态，证明我说的是对的
Reverting to name-calling suggests that you are defensive
我没问你的意见，把那鬼东西拿开
and therefore find my opinion valid.
I wasn't asking for your opinion.
Bones, get that thing off my face.
这任务可能让我们开战，而且还不道德
Captain, our mission could start a war with the Klingons
and it is, by it's very definition, immoral.
你可以仔细想想，就知道我是对的
Perhaps you should take the requisite time
to arrive at this conclusion for yourself.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
我是瓦勒丝，马可士上将派我当科学官
Science Officer Wallace.
I've been assigned to the Enterprise by Admiral Marcus.
这是我的调职令
These are my transfer orders.
你有要求多一个科学官吗？
You requested an additional science officer, Captain?
我真希望我有
I Wish I had.
卡萝瓦勒丝上尉
"Lieutenant Carol Wallace."
应用物理博士，精通先进武器
"Doctorate in applied physics"
"specializing in advanced weaponry."
蛮厉害的
Impressive credentials.
谢谢
Thank you.
但我回来就没这必要了
But redundant now that I am back aboard the Enterprise.
人多比较好办事
And yet, the more the merrier.
请坐，博士
- Have a seat, Doctor. - Thank you.
各位乘客，准备起飞
Shuttle crew, stand by for lift-off.
不可能！别想要我签名！
No! I'm not signing anything!
把那鬼东西拿走！
Now, get these bloody things off my ship! Captain!
史考特，有问题吗？    - 有
Is there a problem, Mr. Scott?
我刚告诉他，我不会让不明物体上船的
Aye, sir. I was just explaining to this gentleman
that I cannae authorize any weapons on board this ship
史考特说的···    - 去舰桥报到
without knowing what's inside them.
Mr. Scott raises yet another point...
舰长
Report to the bridge.
我知道你担心，但我们需要那些鱼雷
Captain.
Mr. Scott, I understand your concerns,
but we need these torpedoes on board.
光子鱼雷也要靠燃料推进
Due respect, sir, but photon torpedoes run on fuel.
我不知道它们用什么燃料
Now, I cannae detect the type of fuel
因为全被力场包覆
that's in the compartments on these torpedoes
我跟他要详细资料，他却说…
because it's shielded.
Now, I asked for the specifications, but he said...
这是机密
- it's classified. - It's classified.
所以我说没数据就不签名！
So I said, "No specs, no signature!"
舰长
Captain.
飞行检查完毕，可以出发了
Flight check's complete. We're good to go, sir.
谢谢，苏鲁
- Thank you, Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir.
如果没别的事，我还要去调整曲速核
Now if you'll excuse me, sir, I have a warp core to prime.
你给我下来！
Get down!
你的身体读数不对劲
Jim, your vitals are way off.
你去医疗室报到，史考特！
Report to the med bay. Scotty!
你一定要签收那些武器才行
I need you to approve those weapons.
你猜那是什么？    - 我没空听你说教
Do you know what this is, Captain?
I don't have time for a lecture, Scotty.
你知不知道那是什么？
- Do you know what this is? - It's a warp core.
是曲速核
那随时会变成一场放射性灾难
It's a radioactive catastrophe waiting to happen.
磁场只要有一点点变化
A subtle shift in magnetic output
譬如说像是发射几十颗…
from, say, firing one or more of six dozen torpedoes
…内容不明的鱼雷
with an unknown payload
都可能引起连锁反应杀死船上所有人
could set off a chain reaction which would kill
every living thing on this ship.
让那鬼东西上船就是最后一根稻草！
Letting those torpedoes on board the Enterprise is the last straw!
那第一根稻草是什么？    - 啥？
- What was the first straw? - What was the...
稻草多的是
There are plenty of straws.
像舰队没收我的超曲速研究
How about Starfleet confiscating my transwarp equation?
却被狂人用来到处逃窜，是谁给他的？
And now some madman's using it to hop across the galaxy!
史考特，那是我们的命令！
Where do you think he got it from?
这才是我最怕的
We have our orders, Scotty!
That's what scares me.
这显然是一个军事行动
This is clearly a military operation.
怎么会变成这样？
Is that what we are now?
我以为我们是探险家
'Cause I thought we were explorers.
签收那些鱼雷，这是命令
Sign for the torpedoes, that's an order.
那我只能辞去职务
Right, well, you leave me no choice
史考特，别这样
but to resign my duties.
Come on, Scotty.
我别无选择    - 我也没有…
You're giving me no choice, sir. I will not stand by...
You're not giving me much of a choice.
你接不接受我的辞职？
Will you just make an exception and sign...
接受
Do you accept my resignation or not?
Idol
我接受
I do.
史考特，你的职务解除了
You are relieved, Mr. Scott.
吉姆
Jim, for the love of God, do not use those torpedoes.
我求求你，不要用那些鱼雷
Attention.
Warp core anti-matter containment check
in three minutes.
舰长，我很遗憾帕克上将死了
Captain! I'm so sorry about Admiral Pike.
我们都很难过
We all are.
你还好吗？    - 我很好，谢谢
- Are you okay? - Fine, thank you, Lieutenant.
史考特刚才辞职了
Actually, Scotty just quit.
你的男朋友又找各种机会质疑我
And your boyfriend's second-guessing me every chance he gets.
对不起，我不该讲这种话
I'm sorry, that was inappropriate.
有时我真想把他的浏海扯下来
It's just sometimes I want to rip the bangs off his head.
大概是我的问题
- You know, maybe it's me. I... - It's not you.
不是你的问题
不是我？
It's not?
你们吵架了？    - 我不是很想谈…
Wait, are you guys... Are you guys fighting?
和他吵得起来吗？
I'd rather not talk about it, sir.
Oh, my God! What is that even like?
你耳朵痒了吗？
Your ears burning?
舰长抵达舰桥！
Captain on the bridge!
Captain.
契可夫，你常跟着史考特
Mr. Chekov. You've been shadowing Mr. Scott.
你熟不熟轮机系统？    - 很熟
You are familiar with the engineering systems of this ship?
很好
Affirmative, sir.
Good.
你是新的轮机长了，去找件红衣服穿
You're my new Chief. Go put on a red shirt.
是，舰长
Aye, Captain.
苏鲁，收回所有的固定器
Retract all moorings, Mr. Sulu.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
停泊钳 1、2、3 号已解开
Docking clamps one, two, and three are released.
所有的固定器已收回
All moorings retracted.
乌胡拉，准备全船广播
Lieutenant Uhura, open a shipwide channel.
Yes, sir.
契可夫，系统怎么样？
Mr. Chekov, how we looking down there?
所有系统正常    - 收到
- All systems nominal, Captain. - Copy that.
曲速准备就绪
Warp available at your command.
谢谢你，契可夫
Thank you, Mr. Chekov.
我们出发吧    - 是，长官
- All right. Let's ride. - Yes, sir.
频道打开了
Channel open, sir.
企业号全体船员请注意
Attention, crew of the Enterprise.
前任舰长和我们的朋友
As most of you know, Christopher Pike,
克里斯托弗帕克
former captain of this ship and our friend,
…已经过世
is dead.
杀死他的人躲在克林贡母星
The man who killed him has fled our system
and is hiding on the Klingon homeworld,
他以为我们不敢过去
somewhere he believes we are unwilling to go.
我们现在就去讨伐他
We are on our way there now.
马可士上将有令，不能曝露行踪
Per Admiral Marcus, it is essential that our presence go undetected.
联邦和克林贡人的关系已经很紧张
Tensions between the Federation
and the Klingon Empire have been high.
任何挑衅都可能引起星际战争
Any provocation could lead to an all-out war.
我会亲自带队到克罗诺斯的废弃城市
I will personally lead a landing party
to an abandoned city on the surface of Kronos
逮捕逃犯约翰哈里森
where we will capture the fugitive, John Harrison,
把他带回地球接受制裁
and return him to Earth so he can face judgment for his actions.
我们去抓这混蛋吧，通话完毕
All right. Let's go get this son of a bitch. Kirk out.
舰长，你的决定很正确
Captain, I believe you have made the right decision.
我很乐意加入特遣队协助你
If I can be of assistance,
I would be happy to accompany you on the away team.
你很乐意？
You? Happy?
我只是想用你惯用的语气表示肯定
I was simply attempting to use your vernacular to convey an idea.
谢谢你，史巴克
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
All personnel, prepare for the closing of payload bay doors.
史巴克，你吓我一跳
Mr. Spock. You startled me.
你来做什么的？
What are you doing, Doctor?
我来检查这些鱼雷···    - 你误会了
- Verifying that the torpedo's internal... - You misunderstand.
我是问你上船做什么？我查不到调职令
What are you doing aboard this ship?
There is no record of you being assigned to the Enterprise.
一定是出了什么差错
Really? That must be some sort of mistake.
我也这么想，马可士博士
My conclusion as well, Dr. Marcus.
你隐瞒了自己真实身分
Except that you have lied about your identity.
瓦勒丝是你妈妈的姓，我猜你爸是上将
Wallace is the surname of your mother.
I can only assume the Admiral is your father.
史巴克
Mr. Spock.
我知道我没资格要求你
I'm aware that I have no right to ask this of you.
但你不能让他知道我在这…
But please, he cannot know that I'm here...
是轮机室那边让我们退出曲速
Engineering manually dropped us out of warp, sir.
契可夫，你把我的船弄坏了吗？
Mr. Chekov, did you break my ship?
我不知道怎么回事！核心过热了
Sorry, sir. I don't know what happened!
我非紧急停止不可
The core overheated.
可能是冷却剂在漏
I had to activate the emergency stop.
It must be a coolant leak. I need time to find it.
对不起    - 该死
- Sorry, Captain. - Damn it.
苏鲁，我们还距离多远？
Mr. Sulu, time to our destination.
还有20分钟航程
Twenty minutes, sir.
我们现在在敌人领空
That's 20 minutes in enemy space we weren't counting on.
我们得快点，史巴克呢？
All right. We better hop to it.
我在这
- Where's Spock? - Here, Captain.
你和我一起去克罗诺斯
You're coming with me to Kronos.
上尉，你克林贡语行吗？
Lieutenant, how's your Klingon?
很久没说但还好
- It's rusty, but it's good. - Good, you're coming, too.
好，那你也来
你们两个一起去不会怎么样吧？
This isn't going to be a problem, is it, you two working together?
当然不会
Absolutely not.
不确定
Unclear.
等一下航天飞机舱碰头
I'll meet you in the shuttle bay.
你没有要去吧？
Jim, you're not actually going down there, are you?
车子爆胎就不应该抢银行
You don't rob a bank when the getaway car has a flat tire.
等我们回来轮机室也该修好了
I'm sure engineering will have us all patched up
对不对，契可夫？
by the time we get back.
Isn't that right, Mr. Chekov?
对，舰长
Yes, Captain.
我尽力
- I 'll do my best, sir.
苏鲁，舰桥交给你
Mr. Sulu, you have the conn.
我们出发以后
Once we're en route, I want you to transmit
传送讯息到哈里森的位置
a targeted comm burst to Harrison's location.
就说有一堆鱼雷正瞄准他
You tell him you have a bunch of real big torpedoes pointed at his head
他不乖就打爆他
and if he doesn't play nice, you're not afraid to use them.
没问题吧？    - 没有
- Is that a problem? - No, sir.
只是我还没坐过那张椅子
I've just never sat in the chair before.
你没问题的
You're gonna do great.
吉姆！等等！
Jim! Wait!
你刚叫他没有筹码就上赌桌吹牛
You just sat that man down at a high-stakes poker game
with no cards and told him to bluff.
苏鲁是个好人，但他不是舰长
Now Sulu's a good man, but he is no captain.
至少这两小时他是
For the next two hours, he is.
还有不要再用比喻了，这是命令
And enough with the metaphors, all right? That's an order.
把科诺米小艇做好起飞准备
Mr. Sulu, make sure that K'normian ship is ready to fly.
代理舰长苏鲁呼叫2号航天飞机舱
Acting Captain Sulu to Shuttle Bay 2.
把默德事件没收的小艇加好油准备起飞
Please have the trade ship we confiscated
during the Mudd incident last month fueled and flight ready.
寇克舰长即将抵达
Captain Kirk is en route to you now.
准备好出动了
Ready to deploy, Captain.
你们把红制服换掉
Lieutenants, lose the red shirts.
你们要伪装成科诺米军火商，穿上这个
You are K'normian arms dealers. Put those on.
如果出差错，不能牵连到舰队
- Sir? - Look, if this thing goes south,
there can be nothing tying us to Starfleet.
除非你想开战，韩德夫
Unless of course you want to start a war, Mr. Hendorff.
不想
- No, sir. - No, sir.
很好，我也不想
Good. Me, neither.
我侦测到克莎省只有一个人
I am detecting a single life sign in the Ketha Province.
照史考特的数据，应该是约翰哈里森
Given the information provided by Mr. Scott,
this is most likely John Harrison.
苏鲁，我们找到他了，吓吓他
Mr. Sulu, I think we found our man.
You let him know you mean business.
Aye, Captain.
约翰哈里森，你给我听好
Attention, John Harrison.
我是企业号的日清苏鲁舰长
This is Captain Hikaru Sulu of the U. S. S. Enterprise.
一艘载有特种部队的航天飞机正往你那去
A shuttle of highly trained officers is on it's way to your location.
如果你不立刻投降
If you do not surrender to them immediately,
我会发射整批已经锁定你的位置的…
I will unleash the entire payload of advanced long-range torpedoes
…先进长程鱼雷
currently locked onto your location.
给你两分钟考虑
You have two minutes to confirm your compliance.
不合作我就把你炸掉
Refusal to do so will result in your obliteration.
要是想测试我，你就死定了
If you test me, you will fail.
苏鲁…
Mr. Sulu,
提醒我不要惹毛你
remind me never to piss you off.
“克罗诺斯”
We will arrive at Harrison's location
三分钟后会到达哈里森的位置
他应该不会束手就擒
in three minutes, Captain.
It is unlikely that he will come willingly.
他有91.6％的机率会尝试杀了我们
I calculate the odds of him attempting to kill us at 91.6%.
太棒了
Fantastic.
幸好你一点也不怕死
Good thing you don't care about dying.
对不起，我没听清楚
I am sorry, Lieutenant. I could not hear what you said.
我没说什么
I didn't say anything.
其实你肯听的话我就说
Actually, I'd be happy to speak
我想私下讨论    - 你根本不想讨论
- if you're willing to listen to me. - Guys...
Lieutenant, I would prefer to discuss this in private.
You'd prefer not to discuss this at all.
你们真的要现在吵架吗？
Our current circumstances...
Are you really gonna do this right now?
你根本不重视我们之间…让我说完
What never seems to require your undivided focus...
I'm sorry, Captain, just two seconds.
在火山你也没为我们设想
- Okay. - Is us.
At that volcano, you didn't give a thought to us.
你也不想想你死了我怎么办
What it would do to me if you died, Spock.
你一点感觉都没有
You didn't feel anything.
不在乎…不只我生你气，舰长也是
You didn't care.
And I'm not the only one who's upset with you. The Captain is, too.
别把我拖下水
Wha... No, no, no. Don't drag me into this.
她说得也对
She is right.
你说我不在乎死亡是不正确的
Your suggestion that I do not care about dying is incorrect.
有自主意识的生物当然有求生的意志
A sentient being's optimal chance
at maximizing their utility is a long and prosperous life.
又来了
Great.
史巴克，你还是唱首情歌吧
Not exactly a love song, Spock.
你误会了
You misunderstand.
我知道自己会死，才决定压抑感觉
It is true I chose not to feel anything
upon realizing that my own life was ending.
帕克上将死的时候，我和他的意识融合
As Admiral Pike was dying,
I joined with his consciousness
感觉到了他死亡瞬间的感受
and experienced what he felt at the moment of his passing.
愤怒，疑惑
Anger. Confusion.
孤独
Loneliness.
恐惧
Feat
我经历过那些感情
I had experienced those feelings before,
我的星球被摧毁时感受更加倍强烈
multiplied exponentially
on the day my planet was destroyed.
我决定不再感受这样的感觉
Such a feeling is something I choose
never to experience again.
娜欧塔，你以为我压抑感情…
Nyota, you mistake my choice not to feel
…是因为我不在乎
as a reflection of my not caring.
我保证情况正好相反
Well, I assure you, the truth is precisely the opposite.
发生什么事？
What the hell was that?
讯号呢？
What happened? Where's their signal?
中断了，我在试着重新连接
It cut out. I'm working to get them back.
D4级克林贡战舰正在追我们
We are being pursued by a D-4 class Klingon vessel.
我以为这区没有人
I thought this sector was abandoned!
一定是巡逻舰
It must be a random patrol.
坐稳了！
Hold on!
这船没有武装
This ship has no offensive capabilities.
还有我们，把能源全转给我
It's got us. Give me all six fuel cells.
Aye, Captain.
该死！
Damn it!
他们快速逼近，方向285
They're closing fast, bearing 285!
我们可以在那里甩掉他们！
All right, there! There! We can lose them there.
你想穿过那些结构体？这船挤不过去的
If you are suggesting that we utilize the passage
between the approaching structures,
可以的    - 绝对挤不过去
- this ship will not fit. - We'll fit.
可以的！可以的！
- Captain, we will not fit. - We'll fit, we'll fit!
我都说挤得过去的！
- I told you we'd fit. - I am not sure that qualifies.
我不认为那样算
看到他们了吗？
Any sign of them?
还没，我有点担心
- No. Which worries me. - We lost them!
甩掉他们了！
Or they're jamming our scanners.
或者我们的扫描仪被干扰
Or we lost them.
也说不定我们甩掉他们了
他们命令我们降落
They're ordering us to land.
舰长，他们会想知道我们来干嘛
Captain, they're gonna want to know why we're here.
他们会折磨我们
And they're gonna torture us.
拷问我们
Question us.
然后把我们杀了
And they're gonna kill us.
那我们就放手一搏
So we come out shooting.
他们人数众多，火力强大
We're outnumbered, outgunned.
冲出去只有死路一条
There's no way we survive if we attack first.
你找我是因为我会讲克林贡语
You brought me here because I speak Klingon.
让我去和他们讲讲看
Then let me speak Klingon.
这行不通的
This isn't going to work.
这是唯一合逻辑的选择
It is our only logical option.
如果你阻止她，不但会激怒克林贡人
And if you interrupt her now, you will not only incur the wrath of the Klingons
还会激怒乌胡拉
but that of Lieutenant Uhura as well.
我是来帮助你们的
拿去    - 谢谢
- Lieutenant. - Thanks, Captain.
恕我直言
有个逃犯躲在这个废墟
他杀了我们很多人
人类自相残杀关我什么事？
因为你重视荣誉
而这个人没有荣誉
你们的人也会陷入危险
把武器放下    - 有几发鱼雷？
- Stand down. - How many torpedoes?
把武器放下
Stand down!
你用来威胁我的鱼雷…
The torpedoes,
the weapons you threatened me with in your message.
有几发？
How many are there?
72发
Seventy-two.
我投降
I surrender.
我代表克里斯托弗帕克…
On behalf of Christopher Pike,
…我的朋友…
my friend,
…接受你的投降
I accept your surrender.
舰长！
Captain!
舰长
Captain.
把他铐起来
Cuff him.
老骨头，到禁闭室来    - 马上到
- Bones, meet me in the brig. - Be right there.
上尉
Lieutenant.
通知舰队我们逮捕了哈里森
Contact Starfleet, let them know we have Harrison in custody,
等我们修好曲速核就会回去
and we'll be on our way once the warp core is repaired.
Yes, sir.
他为什么会投降？    - 不知道
- Why the hell did he surrender? - I don't know.
我只想知道他如何杀光整队克林贡人
But he just took out a squad of Klingons single-handedly.
看来超人上了我们的船
I want to know how.
Sounds like we have a superman on board.
你检查看看
You tell me.
把手伸出来让我抽血
Put your arm through the hole. I'm gonna take a blood sample.
舰长，为什么我们还不回航？
Why aren't we moving, Captain?
难道是曲速核发生意外故障…
An unexpected malfunction, perhaps in your warp core
正好让你困在克林贡领空？
conveniently stranding you on the edge of Klingon space?
你怎么知道？    - 老骨头
- How the hell do you know that? - Bones.
你会感谢我的意见的
I think you'd find my insight valuable, Captain.
好了吗？
- We good? - Yeah.
有结果就告诉我
Let me know what you find.
不理我的话，全船的人都会死
Ignore me and you will get everyone on this ship killed.
我认为他只是想尝试影响你
Captain, I believe he will only attempt to manipulate you.
我不建议你继续与他对话
I would not recommend engaging the prisoner further.
很快就好
Give me a minute.
让我解释一下情况
Let me explain what's happening here.
你是个罪犯
You are a criminal.
我亲眼看到你滥杀无辜
I watched you murder innocent men and women.
我被授命狙杀你
I was authorized to end you!
你还活着的原因也是因为我
And the only reason why you are still alive
is because I am allowing it.
所以闭上你的嘴
So shut your mouth.
你还想打我打到手抽筋吗？
Oh, Captain, are you going to punch me again
over and over till your arm weakens?
显然你很想杀我…
Clearly you want to, so tell me,
那为什么还留我活口？
why did you allow me to live?
每个人都会做错事
We all make mistakes.
不是，我投降的原因
No. I surrendered to you because,
是因为你虽然刻意隐瞒，却有良知
despite your attempt to convince me otherwise,
you seem to have a conscience, Mr. Kirk.
如果你没有，我也不可能说服你
If you did not, then it would be impossible for me
to convince you of the truth.
23…17…46…11
23-17-46-11.
这坐标离地球很近
Coordinates not far from Earth.
你想知道我为什么这么做
If you want to know why I did what I did,
就去那里看一看
go and take a look.
我为什么要听你的
Give me one reason why I should listen to you.
我有72个理由
I can give you 72.
而且全都在你船上
And they're on board your ship, Captain.
他们一直在这儿
They have been all along.
我建议你随便打开一个
I suggest you open one up.
- Ohoo. - Hey.
你知道我最担心什么吗？
You know what really bothers me, though?
是我做的那些修改和强化的零件
It's the modifications, you know, the enhancements.
竟然这样把我赶走！我只是做对的事！
Right? And then like that, I'm off the ship!
Just for trying to do what's right!
你又做了什么？
And what did you do anyway?
你只是像个蚌壳一直瞪着我！
You just stood there like an oyster,
looking at me!
史考特，我是寇克
What?
Scotty, it's Kirk.
噢，是你啊！
Oh, well now!
这可不是美发男詹姆士舰长吗？
If it isn't Captain James Tiberius Perfect Hair!
你有没有听到？我叫他美发男耶
Did you hear that? I called him Perfect Hair.
你在哪里？    - 你又在哪里？
- Where are you? - Where are you?
你喝醉了吗？
Are you drunk?
我下班时间喝酒不用你管
What I do in my private time is my business, Jimbo.
帮我一个忙，把这坐标写下来好吗？
I need you to help me out with something.
Will you take these coordinates down?
23…17…46…11
23-17-46-11.
你写下来了？
Are you writing?
四个号码，很难吗？
What, you don't think I can remember four numbers?
这么不相信我，第三个号码是多少？
Ye of little faith. What was the third one?
Forty-six.
我不知道你要找什么
I don't know exactly what you're looking for,
但我猜你看到就知道了
but I have a feeling you'll know it when you see it.
鱼雷的事可能被你说中了
You may have been right about those torpedoes.
我就当你是在道歉，我会考虑看看
I will consider that an apology.
And I will consider that apology.
是你自己要辞职的
You are the one who quit.
是你逼我辞职的！
You made me quit!
史考特？
Mr. Scott?
史考特
Scott.
他还真大胆
The nerve of that guy!
我才不帮他！
I am not doing that man any favors!
不帮就是不帮！
No!
好啦好啦
All right, then!
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your corn-fed mind?
你怎么能相信他！
You're not actually going to listen to this guy?
他杀了帕克还差点杀了你
He killed Pike, he almost killed you,
他现在叫你开鱼雷你就开？
and now you think it's a good idea to pop open a torpedo
老骨头，他为什么救我们？
because he dared you to.
Why did he save our lives, Bones?
舰长，他说的有道理
The Doctor does have a point, Captain.
史巴克，别附和我
Don't agree with me, Spock. It makes me very uncomfortable.
我浑身不对劲
Perhaps you, too, should learn to govern your emotions, Doctor.
也许你该学习控制你的情绪，逻辑上…
逻辑？一个疯子想炸掉我们的船…
In this situation, logic dictates...
Logic? Oh, my God! There's a maniac
trying to make us blow up our own damn ship and...
我不知道他为什么投降
That's not it. I don't know why he surrendered,
但不会是要杀我们
but that's not it.
我们要打开鱼雷，问题只是怎么打开？
Look, we're gonna open a torpedo. The question is how.
现在史考特不在
But, Jim, without Mr. Scott on board,
还有谁可以拆炸弹？
who exactly is qualified
to just pop open a four-ton stick of dynamite?
上将的女儿对那鱼雷很有兴趣
The Admiral's daughter appeared to have interest
而且还是武器专家
in the torpedoes and she is a weapons specialist.
或许她可以帮忙
Perhaps she could be of some use.
谁是上将的女儿？
What Admiral's daughter?
卡萝马可士
Carol Marcus. Your new science officer
你的新科学官是用假名登船的
concealed her identity to board the ship.
你打算什么时候才说？
When were you going to tell me that?
有必要才说，就是现在
When it became relevant. As it just did.
鱼雷在武器室吗？
Are the torpedoes in the weapons bay?
早就装填好了，里面到底装了什么？
Loaded and ready to fire. What are they?
不知道，所以我伪造文件跑来想弄清楚
I don't know. That's why I forged my transfer
真的对不起
onto your ship to find out why.
I do apologize for that.
很抱歉我造成你困扰
By the way, if I caused you any problems, I am sorry.
我是卡萝马可士
I'm Carol Marcus.
詹姆士寇克
- James Kirk. - Torpedoes.
鱼雷…
我父亲让我参与所有和他有关的计划
My father gave me access to every program he oversaw,
后来听说他在研发实验性鱼雷
then I heard he was developing these prototype torpedoes.
当我去问他时，他却不肯见我
When I went to confront him about it, he wouldn't even see me.
我才发现鱼雷的纪录都被删除了
That's when I discovered the torpedoes had disappeared
from all official records.
然后他把鱼雷都给我了
And then he gave them to me.
舰长，你比传说中的聪明多了
You're much cleverer than your reputation suggests, Captain Kirk.
我还有传言啊？
I have a reputation?
有啊，我是克丽丝汀查佩的朋友
Yes, you do. I'm a friend of Christine Chapel's.
克丽丝汀啊，她还好吗？
Christine, yes. How is she?
在边疆当护士，她现在开心多了
She transferred to the outer frontier to be a nurse.
很好啊
She's much happier now.
你根本不知道我在说谁吧？
That's good.
You have no idea who I'm talking about, do you?
我们来这做什么？
What are we doing in here?
这个航天飞机可以起飞吗？    - 可以
Is this shuttle prepped to fly?
请你转过去一下    - 为什么？
Of course it is.
- Would you please turn around? - Why?
转过去就对了
Just turn around.
在企业号上拆鱼雷太危险了
It's too dangerous to try and open
one of these torpedoes on the Enterprise.
附近有颗小行星，我可以在那里拆
But there is a nearby planetoid.
I can open one up there.
但我需要有人帮忙
But I will need some help.
转回去啊
Turn around.
转啊！
Now!
舰长抵达舰桥！
Captain on the bridge!
苏鲁，马可士和麦考伊降落了没？
Mr. Sulu,
have Doctors Marcus and McCoy landed on the planetoid yet?
有，他们正把鱼雷搬出来
Yes, sir. They're moving the torpedo into position now.
很好，克林贡人有动静吗？
Good. Any activity from the Klingons?
还没，但我们困在这里，迟早会被发现
Not yet.
But if we're stuck here much longer, they will find us.
乌胡拉
Lieutenant Uhura, did you let Starfleet know
舰队知道已逮捕哈里森的消息吗？
we have Harrison in custody?
我通知了，但还没响应
Yes, sir. No response yet.
轮机室呼叫舰桥，舰长，听到吗？
Engineering to bridge.
Hello. Captain, can you hear me?
契可夫，我只要听好消息
Mr. Chekov, give me some good news.
找到泄漏点了，有些严重，我们在修理
We found the leak, sir, but the damage is substantial.
你知道为什么外泄吗？
We're working on it.
Any idea what caused it?
不知道，但我负完全责任
No, sir. But I accept full responsibility.
我有预感不是你的错，继续努力
Something tells me it wasn't your fault. Stay on it.
航天飞机准备好了
Shuttle is standing by, Captain.
老骨头，谢谢你，马可士要手最稳的人
Bones, thanks for helping out.
Dr. Marcus asked for the steadiest hands on the ship.
我幻想过和美女困在荒废星球上
You know, when I dreamt about being stuck
on a deserted planet with a gorgeous woman,
我可没梦到鱼雷！
there was no torpedo!
麦考伊，我可没叫你去泡妞
Dr. McCoy, may I remind you, you are not there to flirt.
你想要这双神奇的手怎么帮你？
So how can these legendary hands help you, Dr. Marcus?
老骨头！
Bones!
我们得拆开弹头，才能了解它的威力
To understand how powerful these weapons are,
we need to open the warhead.
To do that, we need to access the fuel compartment.
但是这些弹头都已经在待命中
Unfortunately for us,
the warheads on these weapons are live.
宝贝，我帮葛恩人紧急接生过
Sweetheart, I once performed
an emergency C-section on a pregnant Gorn.
八胞胎，而且他们一出生就会咬人
Octuplets.
And let me tell you, those little bastards bite.
鱼雷还难不倒我啦
I think I can work some magic on your missile.
内框里面有很多光纤线路
Dr. McCoy, there's a bundle of fiber optic cables
against the inner casing.
你得切断第23条
You'll need to cut the 23rd wire down.
千万别碰到其它的，知道吗？
Whatever you do, do not touch anything else.
我也没想过
Do you understand?
Right. The thought never crossed my mind.
麦考伊医生
Dr. McCoy,
等我指示，我要绕过引爆装置
wait for my word.
I'm rerouting the detonation processor.
准备好了吗？    - 等不及了
- Are you ready? - And raring.
祝你好运
Good luck.
鱼雷启动了    - 30秒后引爆！
Sir, the torpedo just armed itself.
The warhead's gonna detonate in 30 seconds, sir!
搞什么鬼？我的手卡住了！
What the hell happened? I can't get my arm out!
锁定他们讯号，把他们传送回来
Target their signal. Beam them back right now.
传送器没办法分开麦考伊和鱼雷
The transporter cannot differentiate between Dr. McCoy and the torpedo.
一次得整个传送回来
We cannot beam back one without the other.
马可士，你能拆除它吗？    - 我正在试
Dr. Marcus, can you disarm it?
我正在试
I'm trying. I'm trying
把她救走！
Jim, get her the hell out of here!
不！传送我他就死定了！
No! If you beam me back, he dies!
不要干扰我！
Just let me do it!
10，9…
Ten. Nine.
Eight.
准备好传送马可士博士了
Standing by to transport Dr. Marcus on your command, sir.
4，3…
Four. Three.
该死！
Shit!
成功解除引爆
Deactivation successful,
Captain.
麦考伊，你没事吧？
Dr. McCoy, are you all right?
老骨头！
Bones!
吉姆？
Jim?
你得来看看这个
You're going to want to see this.
“坐标23.17.46.11，木星”
第四小组，把推进器送到12号码头
Delta team, deliver your thrusters to loading dock 12.
星舰复仇号，请求进入建设机棚
U.S.S. Vengeance, bridge crew
requesting entry to construction hangar.
允许进入机棚
Man 1'. You are cleared to enter the hangar.
我需要焊接人员到一号引擎舱
Man 3'. I need a welding team on the number one nacelle.
挖哩…
Holy...
有什么发现？
What have we got?
这招很聪明，燃料箱被拆掉…
It's quite clever actually.
This fuel container's been removed from the torpedo
冬眠舱再放进去
and retrofitted to hide this cryo tube.
他活着吗？    - 还活着
- Is he alive? - He's alive.
但如果想叫醒他
But if we try to revive him
解冻程序出错他就会死
without the proper sequencing, it could kill him.
这科技我不熟
This technology's beyond me.
这很先进吗？
How advanced, Doctor?
不是先进，这冬眠舱是古董
It's not advanced. That cryo tube is ancient.
自从曲速技术成熟以后…
We haven't needed to freeze anyone since we developed warp capability,
就再也不必进行冷冻了
which explains the most interesting thing about our friend here.
这也是这位朋友好玩的地方
他已经300岁了
He's 300 years old.
为什么鱼雷里躺了一个人？
Why is there a man in that torpedo?
所有鱼雷里都有人
There are men and women
in all those torpedoes, Captain.
是我放进去的
I put them there.
你到底是谁？
Who the hell are you?
我是旧时代的杰作
A remnant of a time long past.
基因强化后要带领人类
Genetically engineered to be superior
终结世界大战，带来和平
so as to lead others to peace in a world at war.
但我们却被当成罪犯被放逐
But we were condemned as criminals, forced into exile.
沉睡了几世纪…
For centuries we slept,
希望在醒后世界已经改变
hoping when we awoke, things would be different.
但是自从瓦肯星被摧毁以后
But as a result of the destruction of Vulcan,
星际舰队积极地向境外的象限扩张
your Starfleet began to aggressively search
distant quadrants of space.
发现了我们的船，只有我被叫醒
My ship was found adrift. I alone was revived.
我查约翰哈里森，一年前根本没这个人
I looked up "John Harrison."
Until a year ago, he didn't exist.
约翰哈里森是个虚构人物
John Harrison was a fiction created the moment I was awoken
马可士上将叫醒我来帮助他
by your Admiral Marcus to help him advance his cause.
建立假身分来掩饰我
A smokescreen to conceal my true identity.
我名字叫做可汗
My name is
Khan.
星舰上将为什么需要…
Why would a Starfleet Admiral
一个300岁的冷冻人帮忙？
ask a 300-year-old frozen man for help?
因为我比较强
Because I am better.
哪方面？
- At what? - Everything.
各方面
马可士上将身处和平盛世
Alexander Marcus needed to respond to
却面临战争威胁
an uncivilized threat in a civilized time
他需要有战斗专长的人，就是我
and for that he needed a Warrior's mind.
My mind.
来设计武器和战舰
To design weapons and warships.
你说上将违反所有的规章…
You are suggesting the Admiral
只是为了要利用你的智力
violated every regulation he vowed to uphold
simply because he wanted to exploit your intellect.
他是想利用我残暴的天性
He wanted to exploit my savagery.
只有智力是打不赢的，史巴克
Intellect alone is useless in a fight, Mr. Spock.
你连规定都不敢打破，怎么打断骨头？
You... You can't even break a rule.
How would you be expected to break bone?
马可士上将利用我设计武器
Marcus used me to design weapons.
帮他把星际舰队变成一支战斗军队
To help him realize his vision of a militarized Starfleet.
他派你来发射武器
He sent you to use those weapons.
把我的鱼雷射到无关的星球
To fire my torpedoes on an unsuspecting planet.
然后故意破坏你的船
And then he purposely crippled your ship
让你困在敌境等死
in enemy space, leading to one inevitable outcome.
克林贡人会来寻找攻击者
The Klingons would come searching
for whomever was responsible,
你们根本死路一条
and you would have no chance of escape.
这样马可士就可以准备开战了
Marcus would finally have the war he talked about.
正如他所愿
The war he always wanted.
不，不可能
No. No.
我看到你攻击一群没武装的军官
I watched you open fire
in a room full of unarmed Starfleet officers.
你冷血屠杀了他们！
You killed them in cold blood!
马可士把我的船员抢走了
Marcus took my crew from me.
你是个凶手！
You are a murderer!
他用我的朋友来威胁我
He used my friends to control me.
我把他们藏在武器里
I tried to smuggle them to safety
想要偷偷逃走
by concealing them in the very weapons
I had designed,
但是被发现了
but I was discovered.
我只好自己逃走
I had no choice but to escape alone.
我逃走以后…
And when I did, I had every reason to suspect
马可士一定会杀我所有的同伴
that Marcus had killed every single one
我最爱的一群人
of the people I hold most dear.
所以我就以牙还牙
So I responded in kind.
我的船员…
My crew
就是我的家人
is my family, Kirk.
为了你的家人你有什么做不出来？
Is there anything you would not do for your family?
外围警报！有船以曲速朝我们接近中
Proximity alert, sir!
There's a ship at warp heading right for us.
克林贡人吗？    - 曲速？
- Klingons? - At warp?
不是，我们都知道是谁
No, Kirk.
应该不是，不是从克罗诺斯来的
- We both know who it is. - I don't think so.
It's not coming at us from Kronos.
把他送去医疗室，找6个警卫看好他
Lieutenant, move Khan to med bay.
Post six security officers on him.
舰长抵达舰桥！
Yes, Captain.
Captain on the bridge!
对方多久会到？
ETA of the incoming ship.
3秒钟
Three seconds, sir.
防护罩    - 是的，长官
- Shields. - Aye, Captain.
他们在呼叫我们
They're hailing us, sir.
放上屏幕
On screen.
全船广播，作为纪录
Broadcast shipwide, for the record.
寇克舰长
Captain Kirk.
马可士上将，我不知道你要来
Admiral Marcus. I wasn't expecting you.
你的船看起来真厉害
That's a hell of a ship you got there.
我也没想到你会违反命令
And I wasn't expecting to get word
that you'd taken Harrison into custody
逮捕哈里森
in violation of your orders.
这个嘛…
Well, we...
我们曲速核故障以后，只好改变计划
We had to improvise when our warp core
unexpectedly malfunctioned.
但你早就知道了吧
But you already knew that, didn't you, sir?
我不懂你的意思
MARCUS'. I don't take your meaning.
你不就赶来了吗？来帮我们修理的吧？
Well, that's why you're here, isn't it?
To assist with our repairs?
不然舰队指挥官为什么要来中立区呢？
Why else would the head of Starfleet
personally come to the edge of the Neutral Zone?
他们在扫瞄我们
Captain, they're scanning our ship.
你在找什么，要不要我帮你？
Is there something I can help you find, sir?
囚犯在哪里？
Where is your prisoner, Kirk?
按照规定，我要把可汗带回去受审
Per Starfleet regulation,
I'm planning on returning Khan to Earth to stand trial.
惨了
Well, shit.
你跟他讲话了
You talked to him.
我就怕你会这么做
This is exactly what I was hoping to spare you from.
我冒着风险把那混蛋给叫醒
I took a tactical risk and I woke that bastard up,
believing that his superior intelligence
相信他的超凡智慧能帮我们保护自己
could help us protect ourselves from whatever came at us next.
但我错了
But I made a mistake.
现在他杀的人都算在我头上
And now the blood of everybody he's killed is on my hands.
所以我拜托你
So I'm asking you,
把他交给我
give him to me
让我可以把我的错做个了结
so that I can end what I started.
那我该拿他的船员怎么办呢？
And what exactly would you like me to do
with the rest of his crew, sir?
用他们射克林贡人？结束72条生命？
Fire them at the Klingons? End 72 lives?
顺便引起战争？
Start a war in the process?
是他自己把人放进鱼雷的
He put those people in those torpedoes.
我只是不希望你知道里面是什么
And I simply didn't want to burden you
with knowing what was inside of them.
你看到他一个人能造成多少破坏
You saw what this man can do all by himself.
假如他叫醒其它人会怎么样？
Can you imagine what would happen if we woke up the rest of his crew?
他还说了什么？他是和平使者吗？
What else did he tell you? That he's a peacekeeper?
他在玩弄你，你还看不出来？
He's playing you, son, don't you see that?
可汗和他的船员都是被判死刑的战犯
Khan and his crew were condemned to death as war criminals.
我们应该执行死刑以免别人再受害
And now it is our duty to carry out that sentence
before anybody else dies because of him.
我再要求你一次！
Now, I'm going to ask you again!
最后一次
One last time, son.
降下防护罩
Lower your shields.
告诉我他在哪里
Tell me where he is.
他在轮机室
He's in engineering, sir.
我会把他送去传送室
But I'll have him moved
to the transporter room right away.
接下来就交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
苏鲁，千万不要降下防护罩
Do not drop those shields,
你明知可汗在医疗室，你有什么打算？
- Mr. Sulu. - Aye, Captain.
Captain, given your awareness
of Khan's true location in the med bay,
may I know the details of your plan?
我说过要把逃犯带回地球
I told Marcus we were bringing a fugitive back to Earth.
我还打算这么做
That's what we're going to do.
契可夫，我们有曲速了吗？
Mr. Chekov, can we warp?
如果强行启动可能会严重损坏核心
Sir, if we go to warp,
we run the risk of seriously damaging the core!
可不可以？
Can we do it?
技术上可以，但我不建议
Technically, yes, but I would not advise it, Captain.
知道了
Noted.
苏鲁，设定航向回地球
Mr. Sulu, set course for Earth.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
出发
Punch it.
至少船又开了
Well, at least we're moving again.
你以为进曲速就安全的话，那你就错了
If you think you're safe at warp, you're wrong.
联络舰队
Lieutenant Uhura, contact Starfleet.
说我们被不明联邦船舰追赶至中立区
Tell them we were pursued into the Neutral Zone
by an unmarked Federation ship.
通讯系统故障了
Comms are down, sir.
请求允许进入舰桥    - 马可士
Permission to come on the bridge.
Dr. Marcus.
他会追上来，但我能阻止他摧毁这艘船
He's gonna catch up with us, and when he does,
the only thing that's gonna stop him destroying
你得让我跟他谈一谈
this ship is me, so you have to let me talk to him.
我们在曲速，他追不上的
Carol, we're at warp. He can't catch up with us.
他的船有先进的曲速科技
Yes, he can. He's been developing a ship
舰长！这个读数我看不懂
that has advanced warp capabilities...
Captain! I'm getting a reading I don't understand.
我们在哪里？    - 离地球23万公里
- Where are we? - We're 237,000 kilometers from Earth.
损害报告！
- Damage report! - Weapons are way down.
武器失效，毫无防御
- Shields are dropping. - We're defenseless, sir.
舰身已有破裂
Sir, we have a bulkhead breach.
哪里损坏？    - 舰身严重破损
- Where's the damage? - Major hull damage, Captain.
紧急闪避动作！赶快逃到地球
Evasive maneuvers! Get us to Earth! Right now!
听好！你不让我跟他讲话，大家都会死
Captain! Stop! Everybody on this ship is going to die
if you don't let me speak to him.
乌胡拉，呼叫他们
Uhura, hail him.
爸爸，我是卡萝
Sir. It's me. It's Carol.
你在那艘船上做什么？
What are you doing on that ship?
我听到你刚说的话
I heard what you said.
你说你错了，现在想要弥补
That you made a mistake
and now you're doing everything you can to fix it.
但是，爸爸…
But, Dad,
我不相信养我长大的人
I don't believe that the man who raised me
会杀死全船无辜的人
is capable of destroying a ship full of innocent people.
如果我错了…
And, if I'm wrong about that,
你得一起把我杀了才行
then you're gonna have to do it with me on board.
卡萝，我不必连你一起杀
Actually, Carol, I won't.
Oh.
能不能拦截传送讯号？
- Jim... - Can we intercept the transport signal?
没办法
No, sir.
Carol!
寇克舰长，你擅自与哈里森结盟
Captain Kirk, without authorization
and in league with the fugitive John Harrison,
叛变并进入敌人领域
you went rogue in enemy territory,
逼我不得不追捕并摧毁你
leaving me no choice
but to hunt you down and destroy you.
锁定光炮    - 等等！等一下！
- Lock phasers. - Wait, sir, wait, wait, wait!
有话快说
I'll make this quick.
舰尾鱼雷瞄准企业号舰桥
Target all aft torpedoes on the Enterprise bridge.
我的船员只是听我的命令
Sir, my crew was just following my orders.
我为我的行为负全责，让我一个人负责
I take full responsibility for my actions.
But they were mine and they were mine alone.
我把可汗的位置告诉你，不要杀我船员
If I transmit Khan's location to you now,
all that I ask is that you spare them.
拜托你
Please, sir.
我什么都愿意做
I'll do anything you want.
放他们一条生路
Just let them live.
这道歉还真诚恳
That's a hell of an apology.
这样讲好了，我本来也没想留活口
But if it's any consolation,
I was never going to spare your crew.
准备好就…
Fire when...
对不起
I'm sorry.
武器没办法发射！
Our weapons won't fire, sir!
防护罩失效了！
Our shields are down! We're losing power!
有人从轮机室重新启动所有系统
Someone in engineering just manually reset our systems!
什么叫“有人”？是谁？
What do you mean, "someone"? Who?
他们武器系统关闭了
Their weapons have powered down. Sir.
企业号！你们听得到吗？
Enterprise! Can you hear me?
史考特！
Scotty!
猜猜我在木星找到了什么？
Guess what I found behind Jupiter.
你在他们船上！    - 我溜进来的
- You're on that ship! - I snuck on.
我刚做的事是叛国罪
And seeing as I've just committed an act of treason
我真的很想下船
against a Starfleet Admiral, I'd really like
快把我传送回去！
to get off this bloody ship. Now beam me out!
你真是个奇葩，我们现在能源不太够
You're a miracle worker.
We're a little low on power right now.
等一下
Just stand by. Stand by.
能源不足？企业号怎么了吗？
What do you mean, "low on power"?
What happened to the Enterprise?
我等下再打给你
Call you back.
史考特！
Scotty!
史巴克，我们的船怎么样了？
Spock. Our ship, how is she?
我们没什么能做的，不能打也不能逃
Our options are limited, Captain.
We cannot fire and we cannot flee.
还有一件事能做
There is one option.
联络上史考特就转接给我    - 好的
Uhura, when you get Scotty back,
- patch him through. - Yes, sir.
史巴克，舰桥交给你
Mr. Spock, you have the conn.
舰长，我强烈反对
Captain, I strongly object.
反对什么？我什么都没说
To what? I haven't said anything yet.
既然我们不能从外面攻击
Since we cannot take the ship from the outside,
只能从内部破坏
the only way we can take it is from within.
由于大批登舰部队会被发现
And as a large boarding party would be detected,
只能越少人越好
it is optimal for you to take
as few members of the crew as possible.
你会和敌人交战
You will meet resistance, requiring personnel
需要有人善于战斗又熟悉内部
with advanced combat abilities
and innate knowledge of that ship.
显然你想和可汗结盟
This indicates that you plan to align with Khan,
一个我们本来要杀的人
the very man we were sent here to destroy.
我没有要和他结盟，是利用他
I'm not aligning with him, I'm using him.
敌人的敌人就是我朋友
"The enemy of my enemy is my friend."
讲这句阿拉伯俗语的王子后来被砍头了
An Arabic proverb attributed to a prince who was
betrayed and decapitated by his own subjects.
这句话还是很酷
Still, it's a hell of a quote.
我也一起去    - 不，你要坐镇舰桥
- I will go with you, Captain. - No, I need you on the bridge.
我不能让你这么做
I cannot allow you to do this.
我的责任就是让你做最明智的决定
It is my function aboard this ship to advise you
on making the wisest decisions possible,
我确定你不知道怎么做最好
something I firmly believe
you are incapable of doing in this moment.
你说得对
You're right!
我做事没有道理、不合逻辑，只凭冲动
What I'm about to do, it doesn't make any sense,
it's not logical. It is a gut feeling.
我不知道我该做什么
I have no idea what I'm supposed to do.
我只知道我能做什么
I only know what I can do.
企业号需要有能力的人来指挥
The Enterprise and her crew need someone
in that chair that knows what he's doing.
那个人不是我
And it's not me.
是你
It's you, Spock.
告诉我那艘船的一切
Tell me everything you know about that ship.
无畏级战舰，两倍大、三倍快
Dreadnought class.
Two times the size, three times the speed.
先进武器系统，只需少数船员操控
Advanced weaponry. Modified for a minimal crew.
和一般联邦星舰不同，这是战舰
Unlike most Federation vessels, it's built solely for combat.
我会尽全力让你得到应有的制裁
I will do everything I can
to make you answer for what you did.
但我现在需要你帮助
But right now I need your help.
我有什么好处？
In exchange for what?
你说愿意为船员付出一切
You said you'd do anything for your crew.
我可以保证他们安全    - 拜托
- I can guarantee their safety. - Captain.
你连你自己船员都保不住了
You can't even guarantee the safety of your own crew.
老骨头，你弄那个小毛怪干嘛？
Bones, what are you doing with that tribble?
牠死了
The tribble's dead.
我在注射可汗的血小板进牠的身体
I'm injecting Khan's platelets into the deceased tissue of a necrotic host.
他的细胞再生非常快，我想知道为什么
Khan's cells regenerate like nothing I've ever seen,
and I want to know why.
你到底跟不跟我去？
You coming with me or not?
你有没有搞错？
You want to do what?
我们要过去，苏鲁正在把船对准
We're coming over there. Sulu's maneuvering
the Enterprise into position as we speak.
来这艘船？怎么来？
To this ship? How?
7号船舱有个卸货门，编号101A
There's a cargo door, hangar 7, access port 101A.
你要手动打开闸门
You need to find the manual override to open that airlock.
你疯了吗？还有你是谁啊
Are you crazy? Whoever you are.
照他的话做，不会有问题的
Just listen to him, Scotty. It's gonna be all right.
当然有问题
It is not gonna be all right.
你叫我打开通往太空的闸门
You want me to open an airlock into space,
要是掉出去我会冻死然后爆开！
whereupon I will freeze, die and explode!
我们能从这里联络新瓦肯星吗？
Lieutenant, from our current position, is it possible
to establish contact with New Vulcan?
我尽力试试    - 谢谢
- I'll do my best. - Thank you.
苏鲁，对方的状态如何？
Mr. Sulu, what is the status of the other ship?
他们系统还没恢复，我正在把船对准
Their systems are still offline.
I'm aligning our ship now.
史考特，状况怎么样？
Scotty, how we doing over there?
我真希望我有好消息
Captain, I wish I had better news.
计算机接口操控已被限制，武器还有…
They've locked out access to the ship's computer.
They'll have full weapons in
3分钟就会修复
three minutes.
下次我就没办法阻止他们了，稍候
That means next time I won't be able to stop them
destroying the Enterprise. Stand by.
我们的垃圾排放口瞄准101A闸门了
Commander, our trash exhaust is aimed at
access port 101A of the other ship.
舰长，已经瞄准好了
Captain, the ships are aligned.
收到
Copy that.
我到船舱了，再等一下
- Scotty! - I'm in the hangar. Give me a minute.
我快跑到了，等等
I'm running. Stand by.
等等，舰长，这门太小了
Whoa, whoa, hold on, now, Captain.
This door is very wee. I mean, you know, small.
超级小，顶多4平方米大
It's four square meters, tops.
就像从车上跳进桥下的酒杯一样
It's gonna be like jumping out of a moving car,
off a bridge, into your shot glass.
没关系，我跳过
It's okay. I've done it before.
上次是往下跳，我们是跳到一个…呃…
Yeah, it was vertical.
We jumped onto a... it was a...
不重要啦
It doesn't matter. Scotty...
你找到手动开关了吗？
Did you find the manual override?
The manual override, Scotty.
还没啦
Not yet, not yet.
舰长，两艘船中间有很多残骸
Captain, before you launch, you should be aware there is
a considerable debris field between our ships.
史巴克别吵，史考特，好了没？
- Spock, not now. Scotty, you good? - It's not easy!
没那么简单，等我一下好不好，疯子
Just give me two seconds, all right, you mad bastard!
告诉我这行得通
Tell me this is gonna work.
我没把握也没信心这样说
I have neither the information
nor the confidence to do so, Doctor.
舰长，请稍候
Okay, Captain, stand by.
你还真会安慰人啊
Boy, you're a real comfort.
快点、快点、快点
Come on, come on, come on.
好了，我可以开门了
Yes!
Okay, okay! I'm set to open the door.
准备好了吗？
You ready?
那你呢？
Are you?
史巴克，开始吧
Spock, pull the trigger.
是的
Yes, Captain.
发射程序倒数
Launching activation sequence on
three,
two,
ODE.
寇克会撞到432方向的物体
Sir, Kirk is headed for collision at .432!
舰长，正前方有残骸
Captain, there is debris directly ahead.
收到
Copy that.
吉姆，你偏离航道了
Whoa! Jim, you're way off course!
我知道！我看得出来
I know, I know! I can see that.
不许动
Don't move.
用屏幕上的罗盘，你要修正37.243度
Use your display compass, Captain.
You must correct precisely
- 37.243 degrees. - Got it.
我正在往回修正
I'm working my way back.
史考特，你会开门吧？
Scotty, you're gonna be ready with that door, right?
你在这做什么？
What are you doing in here?
来修理这个闸门控制台，你个子真高
Wee bit of maintenance on the airlock console. You're big.
史考特，你在哪里？
Mr. Scott, where are you?
舰长，他好像听不到你，我重新接通他
Captain, he can't seem to hear you.
I'm working on getting his signal back. Stand by.
该死    - 怎么了？
- Damn it. - Captain, what is it?
头盔受损了，乌胡拉，接通史考特没？
My helmet was hit.
Uhura, tell me you have Mr. Scott back.
还没
Not yet. I'm still working on a signal.
通讯器没问题，不知道为什么他不回答
His communicator is working.
那是什么？
- I don't know why he isn't responding. - What is that?
你是舰队还是佣兵？
Are you Starfleet or private security?
另一只手伸出来
Show me your other hand.
你看起来像佣兵
Because you look like private security.
很快就要撞上去了
Imminent collision detected!
可汗，快闪避！前方有残骸
Khan, use evasive action!
我看到了
- There is debris directly ahead. - I see it.
苏鲁，可汗死了吗？
Mr. Sulu, did we lose Khan?
我不知道，残骸太多没办法侦测
I don't know, Commander. I'm having trouble
tracking him in all this debris.
可汗被撞了吗？
Was Khan hit?
我们还在搜寻他
We are trying to find him now.
舰长你得朝183.473方向前进
Captain, you need to adjust your target destination
to 183 by 473 degrees.
我的屏幕坏了，我不能定位
Spock, my display's dead. I'm flying blind.
没有罗盘的话几乎不可能命中目标
Captain, without your display compass,
hitting your target destination is mathematically impossible.
史巴克，等我回来
Spock, if I get back,
一定要教教你怎么说话
we really need to talk about your bedside manner.
中校，他不会成功的
Commander, he's not going to make it.
我的屏幕还是正常的
My display is still functioning.
寇克，你在我前方200米一点钟方向
I see you, Kirk, you're 200 meters ahead of me
往左转几度然后跟着我
at my one o'clock.
Come to your left a few degrees and follow me.
我们快到了，你准备好欢迎我们了吗？
Scotty, we're getting close. We need a warm welcome.
Do you copy? Do you copy? Scotty?
如果你听得到，10秒后开门
If you can hear us, Mr. Scott,
- open the door in ten, nine... - Scotty!
是谁在倒数？
That person counting down,
是你幻听啦
- what is that? - Eight...
I think you're hearing things, mate.
史考特，你在哪里？
- Seven... - Mr. Scott, where are you?
距离1800米…1600米
- Six, five... - 1,800 meters. 1,600 meters.
史考特，你死到哪去了？    - 3…
- Scotty, where are you? - Three...
你听得到吗，史考特！
- Do you copy, Scotty? Please! - Two...
真的很抱歉    - 什么？
- Sorry about this. - About what?
史考特，快开门！    - 开门啊！
- Mr. Scott, open the door! - Open the door!
就是现在！
Mr. Scott, now!
欢迎光临
Welcome aboard.
史考特，真高兴能见到你
- It's good to see you, Scotty. - Who is that?
这谁啊？
这是史考特，这是可汗
Khan, Scotty. Scotty, Khan.
哈啰
Hello.
他们会发现我们的
They'll know we're here.
我知道去舰桥的快捷方式
I know the best way to the bridge.
光炮锁在电晕的程度
It's locked to stun.
他们可不会这么好心
Theirs won't be.
那就不要被他们射中
Try not to get shot.
中校，已经连上线了
Commander, I have that transmission as requested.
请接上屏幕
On screen, please.
稍候
Stand by.
史巴克，你好
Mr. Spock.
上将
Admiral.
我晚点再来处置你…
I'll deal with you in a...
我以当你女儿为耻
I am ashamed to be your daughter.
第13层的一个船舱门刚被打开
Sir, we just had a hangar door open on deck 13.
可汗
Khan.
他们都要恢复动力了，我们还用走的？
They're going to have full power and we're walking?
坐电梯容易被发现，而且逃不了
The turbolifts are easily tracked
and Marcus would have us in a cage.
这信道旁边就是引擎室
This path runs adjacent to the engine room.
他们在这里开枪会影响曲速核
They know they won't be able to use their weapons here
所以对我们有利
without destabilizing the warp core,
which gives us the advantage.
你打哪找到这家伙的？
- Where'd you find this guy? - It's a long story.
说来话长
I Will be brief.
我长话短说
你有没有碰过可汗这个人？
In your travels, did you ever encounter a man named Khan?
你知道我曾发誓不会告诉你…
As you know,
I have made a vow never to give you information
任何会影响你命运的事
that could potentially alter your destiny.
你的路要由你自己走
Your path is yours to walk, and yours alone.
话虽如此…
That being said,
可汗努宁辛格是企业号所碰过…
Khan Noonien Singh is the most dangerous adversary
最可怕的敌人
the Enterprise ever faced.
他非常聪明、无情…
He is brilliant, ruthless,
而且毫不犹豫就会杀光你们
and he will not hesitate to kill
every single one of you.
你打败他了吗？
Did you defeat him?
付出了惨痛的代价才打败他
At great cost. Yes.
怎么打败的？
How?
我不想触霉头，不过人都到哪里去了？
I don't mean to tempt fate here, but where is everybody?
这艘船不需太多人操作，一个人都能飞
The ship is designed to be flown by minimal crew,
one, if necessary.
One? I...
你还好吧？    - 还好，可汗呢？
- You all right? - Yeah. Where's Khan?
找所有高阶医疗和轮机人员去武器室
Lieutenant, I need you to assemble all senior medical
and engineering staff in the weapons bay.
好的
All right.
麦考伊你误触鱼雷的方法，能重复吗？
Dr. McCoy, you inadvertently activated a torpedo.
Could you replicate the process?
我干嘛要再来一次？
Why the hell would I want to do that?
你能不能？
Can you or can you not?
该死，我是医生，不是鱼雷工程师！
Damn it, man, I'm a doctor, not a torpedo technician!
就因为你是医生，请仔细听好
The fact that you are a doctor is precisely
why I need you to listen very carefully.
他跑哪去了？
Where is he?
靠！
Shit!
这里
This way.
我们一到舰桥就电晕他
The minute we get to the bridge, drop him.
电晕可汗？我以为他在帮我们
What, stun him? Khan? I thought he was helping us.
我想应该是我们在帮他
I'm pretty sure we're helping him.
能源已经恢复了！
Power coming online, sir!
重新锁定企业号    - 是的
Retarget the Enterprise now.
Aye, sir.
别让他爬起来
Make sure he stays down.
借过
- Excuse me. - Yeah.
马可士上将，你被逮捕了
Admiral Marcus, you're under arrest.
你不是认真的吧？
You're not actually going to do this, are you?
上将，站起来
Admiral, get out of the chair.
你先想一想自己在做什么
You better stop and think about what you're doing, Kirk.
想想你在克罗诺斯做了什么
You better think about what you did on Kronos.
你入侵敌人星球，歼灭克林贡巡逻队
You made an incursion onto an enemy planet!
You killed a Klingon patrol.
就算你成功离开，还是免不了开战
Even if you got away without a trace, war is coming.
谁来率领军队？你吗？
And who is going to lead us? You?
如果没有我坐镇，大家都别想活了！
If I'm not in charge,
our entire way of life is decimated!
如果你想要我离开这艘船
So you want me off this ship,
你就杀了我吧
you better kill me.
我不会杀你的
I'm not going to kill you, sir.
但我可以电晕你，把你拖下来
But I could stun your ass and drag you out of that chair.
我只是不想让你在女儿面前丢脸
I'd rather not do that in front of your daughter.
你还好吗？    - 还好，舰长
- You all right? - Yes, Captain.
"- Jim!"
听我说！
Listen! Wait!
等等！
你这家伙…
You...
你应该让我一直冬眠下去
You should have let me sleep.
舰长在哪里？
Where is the Captain, Mr. Sulu?
传感器坏了，我找不到他
Our sensor array's down, sir. I can't find him.
我说得简单一点吧
I'm going to make this very simple for you.
用我的船员换你船员的命
- Captain. - Your crew for my crew.
你背叛我们
You betrayed us.
你还真聪明，史巴克
You are smart, Mr. Spock.
史巴克，不要…
Spock don't...
史巴克，把我的船员还我
Mr. Spock, give me my crew.
他们交给你以后，你要做什么？
And what will you do when you get them?
继续我们被放逐前的目标
Continue the work we were doing before we were banished.
按照我所听说的
Which, as I understand it, involves the mass genocide
也就是消灭你们认为比较落后的生命
of any being you find to be less than superior.
我该摧毁你吗？
Shall I destroy you, Mr. Spock?
还是你把我要的交出来？
Or will you give me what I want?
我们的传送器坏了
We have no transporter capabilities.
幸好我的还能用
Fortunately mine are perfectly functional.
解除你的防护罩
Drop your shields.
这样我就不能确保企业号的安全
If I do so, I have no guarantee
that you will not destroy the Enterprise.
那我们用逻辑来思考吧
Well, let's play this out logically then, Mr. Spock.
首先我会杀了你舰长来表示我的决心
Firstly, I will kill your Captain
to demonstrate my resolve.
如果你还不顺从，我只好杀了你们全部
Then if yours holds, I will have no choice
but to kill you and your entire crew.
如果你摧毁我的船，也会杀死你的人
If you destroy our ship,
you will also destroy your own people.
你们需要呼吸，但我船员不必
Your crew requires oxygen to survive, mine does not.
我只要摧毁…
I will target your life support systems
…引擎后方的维生系统
located behind the aft nacelle.
等你们全部都窒息而死…
And after every single person aboard your ship suffocates,
我就会踩着你们冰冷的尸体
I will walk over your cold corpses to recover my people.
把我的人救回来
所以…
Now,
可以开始了吗？
shall we begin?
解除防护罩
Lower shields.
很明智的决定
A wise choice, Mr. Spock.
我看到72枚鱼雷还在发射管里面
I see your 72 torpedoes are still in their tubes.
如果那不是我的，我会发现的
If they are not mine, Commander, I will know it.
瓦肯人是不说谎的
Vulcans do not lie.
那些就是你的鱼雷
The torpedoes are yours.
谢啦，史巴克
Thank you, Mr. Spock.
我已经照你说的做了
I have fulfilled your terms.
换你了
Now fulfill mine.
寇克…
Well, Kirk,
你该回你船上去了
it seems apt to return you to your crew.
毕竟…
After all,
舰长应该和船共存亡
no ship should go down without her captain.
他用光炮锁定我们了！
He's locking phasers on us, sir!
快放我们出去！
Let us out of here now!
防护罩只剩6％！
Shields at 6%!
那些鱼雷！还要多久？
The torpedoes! How much time, Lieutenant?
12秒
Twelve seconds, sir!
所有船员准备
Crew of the Enterprise,
将有爆炸冲击波
prepare for imminent proximity detonation.
他说什么？什么爆炸？
What's he talking about? What detonation?
是鱼雷，他启动鱼雷了！
The torpedoes. He armed the damn torpedoes!
No!
他们的武器系统被炸坏了
Sir, their weapons have been knocked out.
中校，这招不错    - 谢谢
- Not bad, Commander. - Thank you, Lieutenant.
老骨头！
- Bones! - Bones!
护士！
- Nurse! - I got you. I got you.
马可士博士
Dr. Marcus.
吉姆，真高兴见到你
Good to see you, Jim.
你帮史巴克引爆鱼雷的？
You helped Spock detonate those torpedoes?
当然啰
Damn right I did.
他杀了可汗的船员了！
He killed Khan's crew!
他冷漠，但不残忍
Spock's cold, but he's not that cold.
可汗的人在我这
I've got Khan's crew.
72根人型棒冰，好好的躺在冬眠舱里
Seventy-two human popsicles
safe and sound in their cryo tubes.
这小子！
Son of a bitch!
我们主动力网故障了！
Sir, the central power grid is failing!
转用辅助动力
- Switch to auxiliary power. - Auxiliary power failing, sir.
辅助动力也不行了
我们进入地球的重力范围里了
Commander, our ship's caught in Earth's gravity!
能停下来吗？
- Can we stop? - I can't do anything.
我无能为力
Sorry! Oh, no.
赶快疏散！
Clear the area!
紧急锁定！希望你不会晕船
Engage emergency lockdown! I hope you don't get seasick.
你会吗？    - 会
- Do you? - Yeah.
发布弃船警告
Lieutenant, sound evacuation, all decks.
Aye, sir.
身为代理舰长，我下令弃船
As acting Captain, I order you to abandon this ship.
我会留在这控制维生系统和逃生舱
I will remain behind and divert all power
to life support and evacuation shuttle bays.
Evacuation protocols...
我命令你们弃船！
I order you to abandon the ship!
恕我冒犯，但我们也要留下来
All due respect, Commander, but we're not going anywhere.
Attention all decks.
Evacuation protocols initiated.
我才离开一天！一天而已！
One day I've been off this ship! One bloody day!
重力系统故障，抓稳了
Gravity systems are failing. Hold on! Hold on!
所有船员注意，撤退程序启动
Attention, all decks.
Evacuation protocols initiated.
到指定航天飞机报到准备离舰
Proceed to exit bays
- and report to your assigned shuttle.
如果没动力来稳住这艘船，谁也逃不了
There won't be time for evacuation
if we don't get power to stabilize the damn ship!
可以恢复吗？    - 要去轮机室
- Can we restore it? - Only from engineering.
我们得到曲速核那里
We have to get back to the warp core.
- Attention all decks.
吉姆？
Jim?
史考特，我们得恢复动力，快！
Scotty, we got to get the power back on! Come on!
史考特，我们要跳过去！
- Scotty, we got to jump! - What?
跳啊！
Jump! Jump!
天啊
Oh, God.
紧急动力剩15％，还在减少中
Emergency power at 15% and dropping.
所有船员注意，撤退程序启动
Attention, all decks.
Evacuation protocols initiated.
到指定航天飞机报到准备离舰
Proceed to exit bays and report to your assigned shuttle.
吉姆？    - 撑住！
- Jim? - Hold on!
我不行了
I can't.
舰长我来了！
I've got you, Captain!
契可夫    - 别放手！
- Chekov. - Don't let go!
就算曲速核上线，还得转接能源输出
Even if we get the warp core online, we've still got to redirect the power!
他说的对！    - 什么意思？
- He's right, Captain! - What are you talking about?
有人得去用手动开关，那是在…
Someone has to hit the manual override.
…偏导碟的后方！我去！
Laddie, there's a switch...
Behind the deflector dish! I'll flip the switch!
我们走吧！
Let's go!
Oh, no.
Ov-vov! Ov-vov! Ov-vov-vov!
撤退程序启动，到指定航天飞机报到
Evacuation protocols initiated.
Proceed to exit bays and report to your assigned shuttle.
苏鲁，所有动力转入稳定器
Mr. Sulu, divert any remaining power to stabilizers.
我尽力在做
Doing what I can, sir. Doing what I can.
曲速核校准偏离，危险
Core misaligned. Danger.
噢不，完了！
- Oh, no, no, no, no! - What?
框架歪了！没办法转接动力了！
The housings are misaligned!
There's no way we can redirect the power!
这艘船完蛋了，没救了
The ship's dead, sir. She's gone.
还有救
- No, she's not. - Wait, Jim!
进去就死定了！辐射会杀了我们！
If we go in there, we'll die!
Do you hear me? The radiation will kill us!
你听我说好不好？你到底想干什么？
Will you listen to me? What the hell are you doing?
我要进去
I'm opening the door. I'm going in.
这道门就是为了防止辐射外泄
That door is there to stop us from getting irradiated!
我们还没爬上去就会死掉！
We'd be dead before we made the climb!
我没有要你爬
You're not making the climb.
Danger. Core misaligned.
曲速核校准偏离
如果没动力或防护罩
If we don't get power or shields back online,
我们会烧死在大气层
we're gonna be incinerated on re-entry!
曲速核上线了！
Warp core is back online!
苏鲁，推进器开到最大！
Maximum thrusters, Mr. Sulu!
已开到最大！请稍候
Thrusters at maximum! Stand by! Stand by!
防护罩恢复了！    - 我们有动力了
- Shields restored! - Commander, power online.
高度稳住了
Mr. Spock, altitude stabilizing.
这真是奇迹
It's a miracle.
没有奇迹这种事
There are no such things.
轮机室呼叫舰桥，史巴克！
Engineering to bridge.
你最好过来这里
- Mr. Spock! - Mr. Scott.
Sir, you'd better get down here.
越快越好
Better hurry.
把门打开
Open it.
污染清除程序还没完成
The decontamination process is not complete.
辐射会扩散到整个区域，门已上锁
You'd flood the whole compartment.
The door's locked, sir.
我们的船怎么样了？
How's our ship?
安全了
Out of danger.
你救了所有船员
You saved the crew.
你利用他最想要的东西对付他
You used what he wanted against him.
那招很棒
That's a nice move.
换作是你也会那么做
It is what you would have done.
而这…
And this,
…换作是你也会这么做
this is what you would have done.
这么做很合逻辑
It was only logical.
我很害怕，史巴克
I'm scared, Spock.
教我如何不害怕
Help me not be.
你是怎么选择不去感觉？
How do you choose not to feel?
我不知道
I do not know.
我现在没办法控制
Right now I am failing.
我希望你了解为什么我不能任由你丧命
I want you to know why I couldn't let you die.
为什么我一定要去救你
Why I went back for you.
因为你是我的朋友
Because you are my friend.
可汗！
Khan!
哇靠，差点撞到！
God, that was close!
设定目标，星舰总部！
Set destination, Starfleet Headquarters!
引擎故障，无法保证能抵达目标
Engines compromised.
Cannot guarantee destination.
请确认指令
Confirm order.
确定
Confirm.
搜寻敌舰的生命迹象
Search the enemy ship for signs of life.
不可能有人活下来的
Sir, there's no way anyone survived.
可汗就有可能
He could.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
哇！他一跳就30米！
Whoa! He just jumped 30 meters!
能不能把他传送上来？
Can we beam him up?
故障太严重了，没办法锁定
There's too much damage.
I have no incoming signal.
可是应该还可以把你传送下去
But it may be possible to beam you down, sir.
去抓他吧
Go get him.
准备接收坐标
- Stand by for coordinates. - Yes, sir.
输入3517-2598
Enter 3517 by 2598.
坐标确认
Coordinates confirmed.
快拿一个冬眠舱给我
Get me a cryo tube, now!
把这个人抬出来，用药物维持昏迷
Get this guy out of the cryo tube.
把寇克放进去，这样才能保住他脑功能
Keep him in an induced coma.
We're gonna put Kirk inside.
It's our only chance to preserve his brain function.
可汗的血还剩多少？    - 一滴也不剩
How much of Khan's blood is left?
None.
企业号呼叫史巴克！
Enterprise to Spock. Spoon!
启动冬眠程序
Activate the cryogenic sequence.
麦考伊呼叫舰桥
McCoy to bridge.
我联络不到史巴克
I can't reach Spock. I need Khan alive.
要他留可汗活口
You get that son of a bitch back on board right now!
把那混蛋抓回船上！
他可能可以救寇克
I think he can save Kirk.
能不能把他们传送上来？
Can we beam them up to the ship?
他们一直移动，两个都没办法锁定
They keep moving! I can't get a lock on either of them.
那能不能把人传送下去？
Can you beam someone down?
史巴克！
Spock!
史巴克，住手！
Spock, stop! Stop!
只有他能救寇克
He's our only chance to save Kirk!
是男还是女？    - 男孩
- What is it? - It's a boy.
就叫他吉姆
Let's call him Jim.
你父亲只当了12分钟舰长
Your father was captain of a starship for 12 minutes.
但是救了八百人
He saved 800 lives. I dare you to do better.
你能做得比他更好吗？
别这么惊讶，你只是死了一下下而已
Don't be so melodramatic. You were barely dead.
现在只是输血的后遗症
It was the transfusion that really took it's toll.
你昏迷了两个星期    - 输血？
You were out cold for two weeks.
你辐射伤害太严重，没别的办法
Transfusion?
Your cells were heavily irradiated. We had no choice.
可汗的血？
Khan?
我们抓到他以后，用他的血合成出药剂
Once we caught him,
I synthesized a serum from his superblood.
你会不会想杀人？或极度渴望权力
Tell me, are you feeling homicidal?
Power mad? Despotic?
没有特别想
No more than usual.
你怎么抓到他的？
How'd you catch him?
不是我抓的
I didn't.
你救了我一命
You saved my life.
乌胡拉和我也帮了不少忙耶
Uhura and I had something to do with it, too, you know.
你也救过我，还有全船的…
You saved my life, Captain. And the lives...
史巴克…
Spock, just...
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气，吉姆
You are welcome, Jim.
永远都会有人想伤害我们
There will always be those who mean to do us harm.
为了阻止他们…
To stop them,
我们可能会冒险唤醒自身的邪恶
we risk awakening the same evil within ourselves.
当挚爱被剥夺的当下
Our first instinct is to seek revenge
我们马上会想到复仇
when those we love are taken from us.
但那不是我们的本性
But that's not who we are.
今天我们来参加…
We are here today
企业号的复航典礼
to rechristen the U.S.S. Enterprise,
并且向一年前的…
and to honor those who lost their lives
…罹难者致敬
nearly one year ago.
当帕克把他的船交给我的时候
When Christopher Pike first gave me his ship
他要我朗读舰长的誓言
he had me recite the Captain's Oath,
当时我并不在意那些话
words I didn't appreciate at the time.
但我现在了解，那是要提醒我们…
Now I see them as a call for us to remember
我们的本质…
who we once were,
和我们所信守的理念
and who we must be again.
那段话就是…
And those words?
太空，人类的终极边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的旅程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它未来的五年任务
Her five-year mission,
是为了探索陌生的新世界
to explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢航向人类足迹从未踏至的领域
to boldly go where no one has gone before.
舰长抵达舰桥
Captain on the bridge.
一坐上去就放不下了，对吧？
It's hard to get out of it once you've had a taste,
isn't that right, Mr. Sulu?
舰长这头衔是蛮好听的
"Captain" does have a nice ring to it.
位子交还给你
Chair's all yours, sir.
史考特
Mr. Scott.
曲速核怎么样？
How's our core?
像只猫那么温顺
Purring like a kitten, Captain.
她已经准备好了
She's ready for a long journey.
太好了
Excellent.
别这样，老骨头！会很好玩的
Come on, Bones! It's gonna be fun.
在太空待五年，饶了我吧
Five years in space. God help me.
马可士博士
Dr. Marcus.
很高兴你能加入我们这个家庭
I'm glad you could be a part of the family.
有个家真的很棒
It's nice to have a family.
史巴克
Spock.
舰长
Captain.
我们该到哪里去呢？
Where shall we go?
既然没有人执行过这么长时间的任务
As a mission of this duration has never been attempted,
我相信你的判断，舰长
I defer to your good judgment, Captain.
苏鲁，带我们出发吧
Mr. Sulu, take us out.
是，舰长
Aye, Captain.
Mandarin Simplified